Jonathan (Jack) Holmes

Software Developer

425-802-7216 | jdholmes48@gmail.com

LinkedIn | Github | Instagram

I am a software developer with a passion for solving complex problems and creating unique digital experiences. I possess strong communication skills and creativity that enable me to look at problem-solving from an outside the box perspective. My extensive background in the performing arts working as a professional actor has enabled me to hone my composure under-pressure, focus on the details in the bigger picture, and make me an effective and creative collaborator.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front End: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, React JS, JSX, Material UI, Semantic UI, Bootstrap CSS, Babel, RSpec

Back End: Python, Ruby/Ruby on Rails, Node.js, SQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite, BCrypt, Active Storage, Cloud Storage (S3, Azure)

Other: Socket.io, Git/Github, Visual Studio Code, Figma, OOP, Postman, Asana, Sprinklr

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Dump - Github | Demo

Cultivating the art of the Photo Dump

- Designed almost entirely with customized Material UI components to achieve a clean and cohesive user interface.
- Incorporated a Socket.io server in order to provide users with real-time follow notifications.
- Implemented Rails Active Storage connected to an Amazon S3 bucket to securely store user content in the cloud.

BlogShare - Github | Demo

A crowdsourced catalogue of tech blog posts written by bootcamp students

- Built a front-end that leverages multiple design tools and React libraries (Material UI, React Router, Slide Routes, etc.)
- Seeded JSON data the persists seamlessly with user interaction.
- Constructed multiple filters in the browse page for a more thorough digital experience.

The Meme Generator - Github | Demo

A Javascript application dedicated to sharing and generating the latest memes

- Used SMTP.js and an Elastic Email SMTP Server to allow for email sending capabilities.
- Leveraged Google Fonts and CSS to create custom styling.
- Wrote JavaScript, HTML, and CSS code that is scalable and DRY

EXPERIENCE

Sunday In Brooklyn
Server
Brooklyn, NY
08/2022 - 06/2023

- Performed well under pressure managing a high volume of tasks.
- Effectively and clearly communicated with other members of the team.
- Developed the ability to learn new material in a short amount of time.

The SpaniardNew York, NY

Server

09/2020 - 06/2022

- Remained up-to-date on the latest industry trends and happenings.
- Implemented creative solutions to a variety of issues in a high stress environment.
- Worked well independently as well as collaboratively.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School
Full Stack Software Development Program

New York, NY
10/2022 - 01/2023

- Completed the Software Engineering program, logging close to 600 hours of study.
- Delivered 5 agile web applications on, or before deadlines.

Point Park University

Bachelor of Fine Arts, Musical Theatre

Cum Laude

• Dean's List: 2015-2019

Pittsburgh, PA 08/2015 - 04/2019

Social Factor Community Manager Training Certification

09/2020